A Guide to the University of Virginia Board of Visitors Committee Administrative and Topical Files, 1951-2006
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
University of Virginia Board of Visitors Committee Administrative and Topical Files, 1951-2006
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-1/2/1.061
2076 items, 16 Hollinger boxes, 6.5 linear feet
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
For ten years from the date of creation, access to these records will be granted only under the procedures of the Virginia Freedom of Information Act (Code of Virginia -2.1-340 ff.) or with the specific permission of the Secretary of the Board. Researchers interested in obtaining access to these records should direct a request in writing to the Office of the Legal Adviser, Madison Hall, University of Virginia. Access restrictions may apply under the terms of the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (F.E.R.P.A.).
Acquisition Information
These papers were transferred through Ms. Jeanne F. Bailes, Clerk of the Board of Visitors, Office of the Board of Visitors, on October 16, 2006.
Scope and Content
The collection contains miscellaneous committee, administrative and topical files, including minutes, reports, executive session records, correspondence, and memoranda of the University of Virginia's Board of Visitors, 2,076 items (16 Hollinger boxes, 6.5 linear feet), 1951-2006.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged alphabetically by folder title.
Contents List
- 1951-2003 Athletics, 10 items (Box-folder 1:1)
- 1954-1979 Board Appointments, 62 items (Box-folder 1:2)
- 1980-1987 Board Appointments, 74 items (Box-folder 1:3)
- 2003 Board Meetings - Faculty Retirement Dinner, 29 items (Box-folder 1:4)
- 2002 December-2003 April Board Meetings-Full, 26 items (Box-folder 1:5)
- 2003 April-October Board Meetings-Full, 55 items (Box-folder 2:1)
- 1999 April-2000 Februrary Board Meetings-Full-Executive Session, 23 items (Box-folder 2:2)
- 2000 April-2002 October Board Meetings -Full-Executive Session, 42 items (Box-folder 2:3)
- 2002 October-2003 January Board Meetings-Open, 21 items (Box-folder 2:4)
- 2003 December-2004 February Board Meetings-Open, 21 items (Box-folder 2:5)
- 2004 February-April Board Meetings-Open, 80 items (Box-folder 2:6)
- 2004 May-June Board Meetings-Open, 55 items (Box-folder 3:1)
- 2004 September-October Board Meetings-Open, 36 items (Box-folder 3:2)
- 1995-1999 Budget, 25 items (Box-folder 3:3)
- 2000-2003 Budget, 28 items (Box-folder 3:4)
- 2003 Committee Reports, 1 item (Box-folder 3:5)
- 2003-2004 Committee Summaries, 5 items (Box-folder 3:6)
- 2004-2006 Committee Summaries, 4 items (Box-folder 3:7)
- 2002-2003 Correspondence-Audit and Compliance Committee, 16 items (Box-folder 4:1)
- 2004 Correspondence-Audit and Compliance Committee, 23 items (Box-folder 4:2)
- 2002-2003 Mar Correspondence-Buildings and Grounds Committee, 23 items (Box-folder 4:3)
- 2003 April-June Correspondence-Buildings and Grounds Committee, 24 items (Box-folder 4:4)
- 2003 July-October Correspondence-Buildings and Grounds Committee, 22 items (Box-folder 4:5)
- 2004 January-May Correspondence-Buildings and Grounds Committee, 22 items (Box-folder 5:1)
- 2004 September-December Correspondence-Buildings and Grounds Committee, 18 items (Box-folder 5:2)
- 2003 Correspondence - Diversity, Special Committee on, 29 items (Box-folder 5:3)
- 2004 Correspondence - Diversity, Special Committee on, 23 items (Box-folder 5:4)
- 2003 January-August Correspondence-Educational Policy Committee, 30 items (Box-folder 5:5)
- 2003 November Correspondence-Educational Policy Committee, 17 items (Box-folder 5:6)
- 2004 Correspondence - Educational Policy Committee, 24 items (Box-folder 5:7)
- 2001-2002 Correspondence-Executive Committee, 28 items (Box-folder 6:1)
- 2003 January-March Correspondence -Executive Committee, 18 items (Box-folder 6:2)
- 2003 March-November Correspondence-Executive Committee, 13 items (Box-folder 6:3)
- 2004 Correspondence - Executive Committee, 3 items (Box-folder 6:4)
- 2003 April-October Correspondence-External Affairs Committee, 22 items (Box-folder 6:5)
- 2004 February-April Correspondence-External Affairs Committee, 8 items (Box-folder 6:6)
- 2004 April-October Correspondence-External Affairs Committee, 17 items (Box-folder 7:1)
- 2003 January Correspondence -Finance Committee, 2 items (Box-folder 7:2)
- 2003 April-May Correspondence-Finance Committee, 12 items (Box-folder 7:3)
- 2003 June-October Correspondence-Finance Committee, 11 items (Box-folder 7:4)
- 2004 February-April Correspondence-Finance Committee, 10 items (Box-folder 7:5)
- 2004 May Correspondence - Finance Committee, 27 items (Box-folder 8:1)
- 2004 September-December Correspondence-Finance Committee, 9 items (Box-folder 8:2)
- 2003-2004 Correspondence-Full Board Policy, 13 items (Box-folder 8:3)
- 2005 March Correspondence - Investment Management Company, 1 item (Box-folder 8:4)
- 2005 April Correspondence - Investment Management Company, 3 items (Box-folder 8:5)
- 2005 May Correspondence - Investment Management Company, 2 items (Box-folder 9:1)
- 2005 June-September Correspondence-Investment Management Company, 6 items (Box-folder 9:2)
- 2005 December-2006 March Correspondence-Investment Management Company, 5 items (Box-folder 9:3)
- 2006 May-September Correspondence-Investment Management Company, 2 items (Box-folder 9:4)
- 2003 January-May Correspondence-Medical Center Operating Board, 34 items (Box-folder 10:1)
- 2003 June-September Correspondence-Medical Center Operating Board, 35 items (Box-folder 10:2)
- 2003 October-December Correspondence-Medical Center Operating Board, 34 items (Box-folder 10:3)
- 2004 January-April Correspondence-Medical Center Operating Board, 40 items (Box-folder 10:4)
- 2004 May Correspondence - Medical Center Operating Board, 22 items (Box-folder 10:5)
- 2004 July-September Correspondence-Medical Center Operating Board, 42 items (Box-folder 11:1)
- 2004 October-December Correspondence-Medical Center Operating Board, 28 items (Box-folder 11:2)
- 1997-1999 Correspondence-Student Affairs and Athletics Committee, 17 items (Box-folder 11:3)
- 2002-2003 Correspondence-Student Affairs and Athletics Committee, 32 items (Box-folder 11:4))
- 2003 December-2004 August Correspondence-Student Affairs and Athletics Committee, 43 items (Box-folder 11:5)
- 2004 September-December Correspondence-Student Affairs and Athletics Committee, 17 items (Box-folder 12:!)
- 2002-2004 Correspondence-University of Virginia's College at Wise, 41 items (Box-folder 12:2)
- 2001-2003 Executive Summaries, 10 items (Box-folder 12:3)
- 2004 December Football Game, 14 items (Box-folder 12:4)
- 1991-2001 General Counsel, 18 items (Box-folder 12:5)
- 1974-2005 Guerry, Dupont III, 17 items (Box-folder 12:6)
- 2003 January-March Memoranda to the Board, 21 items (Box-folder 13:1)
- 2003 April-July Memoranda to the Board, 32 items (Box-folder 13:2)
- 2003 August-December Memoranda to the Board, 28 items (Box-folder 13:3)
- 2004 January-March Memoranda to the Board, 16 items (Box-folder 13:4)
- 2004 April-July Memoranda to the Board, 19 items (Box-folder 13:5)
- 2004 August-December Memoranda to the Board, 36 items (Box-folder 13:6)
- 2002 Memoranda to the Board, Former Members of, 4 items (Box-folder 13:7)
- 2003 February-October Memoranda to the Board, Former Members of, 5 items (Box-folder 14:1)
- 2003 October-2005 April Memoranda to the Board, Former Members of, 10 items (Box-folder 14:2)
- 2002-2006 Minutes - Audit and Compliance Committee, 14 items (Box-folder 14:3)
- 2004-2006 Minutes - Buildings and Grounds Committee, 9 items (Box-folder 14:4)
- 2005-2006 Minutes - Diversity, Special Committee on, 5 items (Box-folder 14:5)
- 2005-2006 Minutes - Educational Policy Committee, 3 items (Box-folder 14:6)
- 2003-2006 Minutes - Executive Committee, 19 items (Box-folder 14:7)
- 2004-2006 Minutes - External Affairs Committee, 6 items (Box-folder 14:8)
- 2005-2006 Minutes - Finance Committee, 2 items (Box-folder 14:9)
- 2003-2004 Minutes - Investment Management Company, 20 items (Box-folder 14:10)
- 2002-2004 Minutes - Medical Center Operating Board, 25 items (Box-folder 14:11)
- 2004-2006 Minutes - Medical Center Operating Board, 8 items (Box-folder 14:12)
- 2005-2006 Minutes - Student Affairs and Athletics Committee, 4 items (Box-folder 13))
- 2005-2006 Minutes - University of Virginia's College at Wise, Committee on, 4 items (Box-folder 14:14)
- 2005 Minutes to Former Members of the Board, 4 items (Box-folder 15:1)
- 1990-1998 Orientation for new Board Members, 41 items (Box-folder 15:2)
- 1998-2001 Orientation for new Board Members, 8 items (Box-folder 15:3)
- 1962-1978 Retirement Policy (Box-folder 15:4)
- 1980-2005 Smith, Carl, 48 items (Box-folder 15:5)
- 1976-2000 University Relations, 46 items (Box-folder 15:6)
- 1977-2004 Zimmer, William L., III, 79 items, both folders (Box-folder 15:7)
- 1970-1976 Zimmer, William L., III (Box-folder 15:8)